Conor Bailey

07540 809644, conbailey90@gmail.com

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/conor-bailey/, https://github.com/conorbailey90, https://www.youtube.com/c/conorbailey

PROFILE

I am a diligent individual with 12 years experience within Financial Crime Compliance holding various positions in Sanctions, Trade Finance, Fraud, AML transaction monitoring, Technology / Change and data analysis / MI development. I have a large passion for technology being proficient in multiple programming languages including SQL, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Microsoft Visual Basic. I am able to combine my experience and passion for technology and financial crime which allows me to identify potential suspicious / sanctioned activity. My technical knowledge has enabled me to review and calibrate financial crime systems to ensure the full optimization and effectiveness of system scenarios and thresholds.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dec 2019 — Present

S2 Financial Crime Control: Financial Crime Change Analyst / MI Developer, SANTANDER UK PLC

City of London

- Review and calibration of 290 Retail Transaction Monitoring scenarios as part of the Control Acceleration Program (CAP). The project involved recreating Erase (TM system) scenarios using SQL Server and documenting scenario parameters into relevant model manuals.
- Conducted above the line / below the line testing on the output of specific Retail TM scenarios to assess
 their effectiveness.
- Successfully implemented and rolled out the Alert Optimization Tool (AOT) used to consolidate all
 alerting customer activity providing analysts with a holistic view of customer activity. AOT was built using
 SQL Server and Microsoft Access.
- Assisted with the development of an RPA Robot built using Selenium used to automate the process of closing down alerts in source TM systems once they have been worked in AOT.
- Ensure that any AOT / EUC system issues / bugs identified by the transaction Monitoring analysts are rectified in a timely manner.
- Collating CIB/CCB team MI information using SQL Server and VBA programming to report team alert
 completion rate-par-day statistics, transaction insights, and Vostro account activity statistics to identify
 any emerging patterns trends which could impact forecasting figures.

Jul 2018 — Dec 2019

S2 Correspondent / Investment Banking Transaction monitoring Analyst, SANTANDER UK PLC

City of London

- Conducted retrospective AML Transaction Monitoring investigations on alerts generated against activity
 on the banks Vostro / Retail / Corporate client accounts.
- Liaised with Vostro client relationship managers to request further information on alerted suspicious activity where necessary.
- Raising of internal SAR's to the bank's internal SAR unit where potential suspicious activity has been identified.
- Utilizing open source searches as well as internal / external systems (Palantir, Dow Jones, Factiva, Net Reveal, EUC) to build a client profile for all alerted parties in order to make sense of the alerted transaction activity to mitigate financial crime risk.
- Monthly presenting of current financial crime related hot topics, trends, and typologies to the AML CIB TM team.

Jul 2016 - Jul 2018

Assistant Vice President - Financial Crime Middle Office, Sumitomo Mitsui Banking Corporation Europe (SMBCE)

City of London

- Conducting enhanced AML / sanctions screening of all transactions involving SMBC Dubai including checks on all underlying documentation (invoices, transport documents etc).
- Conducting sanctions, dual use goods AML checks on Trade Finance documentation using Fircosoft, Microsoft Access and the EU dual use goods checker.
- Tracking of all shipping documents (BL's, AWB's, CMR's, LoI's) utilizing the carrier websites and Track
 Trace as well as Lloyds List intelligence to verify vessel movements.
- Working closely with the Forensics Department where any Trade Finance red flags are identified (pre/post-dated transport documents, vessel movement discrepancies etc.)
- Liaising with the International Maritime Bureau (IMB) when transport documents are unable to be tracked in house.
- Reviewing live fraud alerts generated in Actimize.
- Reviewing real time system generated hits in the banks sanctions filter (Fircosoft Continuity).

- Managing the timely processing of all incoming and outgoing SWIFT traffic.
- Monitoring daily workflows and Sanction queues adhering to key controls.
- Writing sanctions rules within Fircosoft Continuity to discount repetitive False positives.
- Compiling of monthly management MI reporting.
- Working closely with IT, Compliance, and system Vendors to incorporate system and operational process flow change management and User Acceptance Testing.

City of London

Oct 2008 — Jul 2016

Senior Associate - Compliance Division for EMEA, Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi UFJ (MUFG)

- Supervisor level sign-off for sanctions and AML investigations, trade finance screening and live and post transaction sanction screening, applying current OFAC, HMT, EU and JFEL regime rules, as well as POCA, JMLSG and internally created procedures and best practice.
- Real time sanctions/AML screening of Swift messages, BACS, SEPA and UK low value domestic transactions using the Logica Hotscan payment filter system.
- Sanctions screening of the entire customer database using Finscan.
- Initiating, advising and completing financial sanctions investigations, including regular use of the EU
 Tariff system/goods checker for embargo checks on goods and regular use of Lloyds List Intelligence to
 investigate Trade Finance related shipping movements against sanction program restrictions.
- Compiling monthly, quarterly and annual AML and sanctions reports for MLRO and Head Office.
- Presenter at the Biannual Transaction Monitoring effectiveness meeting.
- Assisting the AML and KYC teams with investigations and sanctions issues which arise.
- Advising Far East and Middle East regions on EU, HMT and OFAC regulations in relation to financial sanctions.

EDUCATION		
Jun 2017 — Sep 2020	Udacity Java Web Developer Nanodegree	City of London
Oct 2019 — Feb 2021	Udacity Data Analyst Nanodegree	City of London
May 2019 — Aug 2019	Udacity Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree (Python Flask)	City of London
Dec 2016 — Dec 2016	ICA Certificate in Managing Sanctions Risk (Distinction)	City of London
Mar 2014 — Mar 2014	ICA Advanced Certificate in AML (Merit)	City of London
HOBBIES	Taking tech courses on Udemy / Udacity. Teaching programming on my Youtube channel (see links), Football and music production.	